Preliminary Guide to the Beverlee A. Myers Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Beverlee A. Myers papers
1957-1988
MS 1461
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
26.5
(27 boxes)
The papers of Beverlee A. Myers consist of correspondence, topical files, reports, speeches, printed material, datebooks, photographs, audiocassettes and a videotape chiefly relating to Myers's career in public health between 1973 and 1986.
Myers, Beverlee A., 1930-1986
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Beverlee A. Myers, 1986; and D. S. Myers, 1987 and 1991.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The papers of Beverlee A. Myers consist of correspondence, speeches, reports, printed materials, photographs, datebooks, audiocassette tapes, and a videotape chiefly relating to Myers' career in public health between 1973 and 1986. The papers were a gift of the estate of Beverlee A. Myers and D.S. Myers in 1986 and 1987.
The bulk of the material consists of topical files containing correspondence, memoranda, reports, and printed material relating to Myers' activities and interests in the field of public health; speeches which Myers presented at meetings and conferences; reprints and photocopies of articles relating to contemporary public health issues; and audiocassette tapes of lectures and conference presentations by Myers and others. Personal papers consist of correspondence, datebooks, photographs, clippings, and awards. In a videotaped interview dated October 11, 1986 (box 20), Myers discusses her appointment as director of the California Department of Health Services by Governor Jerry Brown, and her accomplishments and challenges in that position.
Arrangement
Arranged by record type.
Biographical / Historical
BEVERLEE A. MYERS, 1930-1986
Beverlee A. Myers was born in Berkeley, California, on October 14, 1930. She received the A.B. From Washington University (1951) and the M.P.H from the University of Michigan at Ann Arbor (1962). She held a number of administrative staff positions with the United States Public Health Service and the Department of Health, Education and Welfare between 1962 and 1973, was deputy commissioner for medical assistance, New York Department of Social Services from 1973 to 1976, consultant to the United States and Senate Judiciary Committee from 1977 to 1978, and director of the California Department of Health Services from 1978 to 1982.
From 1974 to 1986 Myers lectured and conducted seminars at a number of universities including the University of Michigan, Johns Hopkins, Yale, and Cornell universities, and the University of California at Berkeley. She was professor and head of the division of health services at the School of Public Health at the University of California at Los Angeles from 1983 to 1986.
Myers was an active member of the Ameican Public Health Association, the American Public Welfare Association, the Association of State and Territorial Health Officers, and the National Council of Public Welfare Administrators.
In addition to numerous articles, Myers wrote A Guide to Medical Care Administration, Vol. 1: Concepts and Principles.
Beverlee Myers died in 1986.
Conditions Governing Access
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Public health administration -- California; Public health -- United States; Educators; Health-officers; Myers, Beverlee A., 1930-1986; California. Department of Health Services
- Topical Files
  - 1982-1987 (Box 1)
  - 1978-1984 (Box 2)
  - 1961-1985 (Box 3)
  - 1975-1985 (Box 4)
  - 1981-1985 (Box 5)
  - 1978-1986 (Box 6)
  - 1974-1986 (Box 7)
  - 1976-1983 (Box 8)
  - 1977-1986 (Box 9)
  - 1982-1986 (Box 10)
  - 1982-1985 (Box 11)
  - 1961-1986 (Box 12)
  - Writings
  - Speeches
    - 1971-1979 (Box 13)
    - 1979-1981 (Box 14)
    - 1981-1983 (Box 15)
    - 1976-1984 (Box 16)
    - 1976-1985 (Box 17)
    - 1979-1986 (Box 18)
  - Papers and Publications, 1961-1985 (Box 18)
- Personal Papers
  - 1960-1984 (Box 19)
  - 1972-1986 (Box 20)
  - 1978-1988 (Box 21)
- Printed Material (Box 22)
- Printed Material (Box 23)
- Printed Material (Box 24)
- Printed Material (Box 25)
- Printed Material (Box 26)
- Audiocassette Tapes, 1984-1986 (Box 27)